MUNICH (GERMANY)
‫"(ميونخ)، (ألمانيا)"‬
Domo. We look forward to working with you.
‫"دومو". نتطلع إلى العمل معكم.‬
Domo. We look forward to it as well.
‫"دومو". نتطلع إلى ذلك أيضًا.‬
Next time, why don't we play a round of golf together?
‫لم لا نلعب الغولف معًا في المرة المقبلة؟‬
All right, but please go easy on us.
‫لا نمانع ولكن يُرجى أن تترفقوا بنا.‬
We look forward to doing more business with you in the future.
‫نتطلع إلى العمل معكم‬ ‫في مشاريع أكثر مستقبلًا.‬
Domo.
‫"دومو".‬
"Domo" this, "domo" that.
‫لا ينفكون عن قول "دومو".‬
All that stuff makes no sense at all.
‫ما منطق في كلامهم.‬
Oh, domo, domo! Sorry to keep you waiting.
‫"دومو"! أعتذر عن التأخر.‬
Our meeting went on longer than expected.
‫طال اجتماعنا عمّا توقعت.‬
I'm Iwai, from Kadofuku Corporation's Munich office.
‫أنا "إواي" من شركة "كادوفوكو"،‬ ‫فرع "ميونخ".‬
I'm Inspector Lunge of the BKA.
‫أنا المفتش "لونغي"‬ ‫من مكتب الشرطة الجنائية الفيدرالية.‬
It's a pleasure to meet you.
‫سررت بلقائك.‬
Domo.
‫"دومو".‬
"Domo" and a bow? Well, I wasn't expecting that.
‫تشكرني بلغتي وتنحني؟ لم أتوقع ذلك.‬
A coffee, please. And give him a refill.
‫قهوة من فضلك. وأعد ملأ كوبه.‬
Inspector, you asked to speak with Yamamoto,
‫طلبت أن تتحدّث إلى "ياماموتو"‬ ‫يا حضرة المفتش،‬
but he's in the Czech Republic for business right now.
‫لكنه في جمهورية "التشيك"‬ ‫في رحلة عمل حاليًا.‬
He should be back tomorrow.
‫سيعود غدًا.‬
He sounds like a busy man.
‫يبدو أنه رجل مشغول.‬
Haven't you heard?
‫ألم تسمع بما حدث؟‬
Now that the mogul Mr. Schuwald
‫بعدما خرج رجل الأعمال المهم "شوفالد"‬
has come out of seclusion and has gotten involved in business again,
‫من عزلته وانخرط في التجارة مجددًا،‬
all his subsidiaries
‫جميع شركاته التابعة ومجالاتها‬ ‫في كافة أنحاء "ألمانيا" نشطت بقوة.‬
All of us Japanese businessmen are busy vying for his attention.
‫وجميع رجال الأعمال اليابانيين‬ ‫يتنافسون على جذب انتباهه.‬
Why's he laughing?
‫لم يضحك؟‬
I'm sorry that Yamamoto can't meet with you today,
‫يؤسفني أنه لن يسعك‬ ‫مقابلة "ياماموتو" اليوم،‬
but I'm just about as familiar with Kenzo Tenma as he is.
‫لكنني على دراية بـ"كينزو تينما"‬ ‫بقدر معرفته به.‬
I see.
‫مفهوم.‬
I was surprised to hear that you're still investigating him.
‫فاجأني سماع أنك لا تزال تتحرّى عنه.‬
Yes. The case still hasn't been solved.
‫أجل. لم تُحلّ القضية بعد.‬
I was shocked when I heard that Mr. Tenma was a suspect.
‫صدمني سماع أن السيد "تينما" مشتبه به.‬
"Shocked?" Was it really so unbelievable?
‫صُدمت؟ أيصعب تصديق ذلك حقًا؟‬
"Unbelievable" isn't a strong enough word. There's no way he's a murderer.
‫بل يستحيل أن يكون قاتلًا.‬
I mean, to be perfectly honest, he could never do anything like that.
‫ما كان ليقدم على فعلة كهذه، لأكون منصفًا.‬
Three years ago, I went out drinking with him a couple of times.
‫قبل ثلاثة أعوام‬ ‫خرجت معه عدة مرات لاحتساء المشروبات معًا.‬
He's not a bad person.
‫ليس شخصًا سيئًا.‬
If he's not a bad person,
‫عدم كونه سيئًا،‬
does that make him a good person?
‫أيعني بالضرورة أنه شخص صالح؟‬
A good person?
‫صالح؟‬
Well, he was more of a reserved person.
‫بل إنه أقرب إلى كونه شخصًا محافظًا.‬
Is a reserved person a good person?
‫هل الشخص المحافظ شخص صالح؟‬
Anyway, what I mean is he wasn't an unfriendly guy.
‫ما أعنيه هو أنه ليس عدوانيًا.‬
Japanese people don't ordinarily wear this kind of thing.
‫ليس من عادة اليابانيين أن يرتدوا‬ ‫هذا النوع من الثياب.‬
Japanese are skillful with chopsticks.
‫وهم ماهرون في استخدام أعواد الأكل.‬
I am Japanese. Domo.
‫أنا ياباني. "دومو".‬
I am Japanese.
‫أنا ياباني.‬
I am…
‫أنا…‬
Tenma.
‫"تينما".‬
Yes?
‫نعم؟‬
Oh… Dad?
‫أبي؟‬
Hi.
‫مرحبًا.‬
How are you?
‫كيف حالك؟‬
I'm fine.
‫أنا بخير.‬
I called because I heard you're in Munich.
‫اتصلت لأنني سمعت أنك في "ميونخ".‬
I live here in Munich now.
‫أقيم حاليًا في "ميونخ".‬
Dad, my child's been born.
‫أنجبت طفلي يا أبي.‬
Is that right? Congratulations.
‫حقًا؟ تهانئي.‬
A lot has happened between us, but I want you to see your grandchild.
‫ثمة خلافات عديدة طرأت بيننا‬ ‫ولكنني أريدك أن ترى حفيدك.‬
Will you come see us?
‫هلّا تأتي لرؤيتنا.‬
Of course.
‫سآتي طبعًا.‬
Great. Can we meet tomorrow?
‫رائع. أيمكننا أن نتقابل غدًا؟‬
Yeah. After 6:00 p.m.
‫أجل. بعد السادسة مساءً.‬
We'll meet in Marienplatz.
‫لنتقابل في "مارين بلاتز".‬
Okay. Good.
‫حسنًا. رائع.‬
Bye. Domo.
‫مع السلامة. "دومو".‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
TACHIBANA
‫"(تاتشيبانا)"‬
Wow. You're pretty good with those chopsticks.
‫يا للروعة. أنت تجيد استخدام أعواد الأكل.‬
Is that so?
‫حقًا؟‬
Lately, there are a lot of foreigners
‫مؤخرًا، ثمة الكثير من الأجانب‬
who use chopsticks better than many Japanese.
‫يجيدون استخدام أعواد الأكل‬ ‫أكثر من الكثير من اليابانيين.‬
Now then, Dr. Takahashi,
‫حسنًا إذًا يا د. "تاكاهاشي"،‬
as Tenma's former co-worker, what was your impression of him?
‫بصفتك زميلًا سابقًا لـ"تينما"،‬ ‫ما كان انطباعك عنه؟‬
My impression? Well, let's see…
‫انطباعي؟ حسنًا، لنر…‬
We got along pretty well.
‫كانت تجمعنا علاقة طيبة.‬
He can be indecisive at times.
‫أحيانًا ما كان يصبح مترددًا.‬
Yet…
‫ومع ذلك…‬
"Yet?"
‫ومع ذلك ماذا؟‬
When he had a scalpel in his hand, he was a different man.
‫عندما يمسك بالمبضع، يصبح رجلًا مختلفًا.‬
He was called a genius neurosurgeon, but it certainly wasn't an exaggeration.
‫كان يُوصف بنابغة جراحة المخ والأعصاب‬ ‫ولم تكن هذه مبالغة.‬
What about his parents?
‫ماذا عن والديه؟‬
He didn't like talking about them.
‫ما كان يحب التحدث عنهما.‬
He said his father and older brother were doctors.
‫قال إن والده وأخاه الأكبر كانا طبيبين.‬
I doubt he had a choice about becoming a doctor.
‫أشك في أنه أصبح طبيبًا بالإكراه.‬
Come to think of it, he told me that after becoming a doctor in Germany,
‫ذكّرني هذا بما أخبرني به،‬ ‫إذ قال إنه بعد أن أصبح طبيبًا في "ألمانيا"،‬
he hadn't been back to Japan even once.
‫لم يعد إلى "اليابان" ولو لمرة.‬
In fact, his parents didn't even come to Germany when the scandal broke,
‫بل وإن والداه لم يأتيا إلى "ألمانيا"‬ ‫بعد وقوع الفضيحة،‬
and didn't even do anything to prove their son's innocence.
‫ولم يفعلا أي شيء لتبرئة ابنهما.‬
I guess you could say they weren't a tight-knit family.
‫يمكنك وصف عائلته بأنها مفككة.‬
KADOFUKU CORPORATION
‫"شركة (كادوفوكو)"‬
I'm terribly sorry about this.
‫أعتذر عن هذا بشدة.‬
Yamamoto just called to let us know he's arriving in Munich from Prague,
‫اتصل بنا "ياماموتو" ليعلمنا‬ ‫بأنه وصل إلى "ميونخ" من "براغ"،‬
but he said he has to go visit a client before returning here.
‫ولكنه أخبرنا بأن عليه أن يزور زبونًا‬ ‫قبل القدوم إلى هنا.‬
He sounds like a busy man.
‫أجده رجلًا مشغولًا.‬
He said he'd drop by the pub we're heading off to now.
‫قال إنه سيمرّ على الحانة‬ ‫التي سنتوجه إليها الآن.‬
"Pub?"
‫حانة؟‬
How about you join us too, Inspector Lunge?
‫ما رأيك في أن تنضم إلينا‬ ‫أيها المفتش "لونغي"؟‬
This could be a good opportunity. You can always use new contacts.
‫قد تكون هذه فرصة جيدة.‬ ‫يمكنك دائمًا الاستفادة من معارف جديدة.‬
Actually, tonight I've got…
‫يتوجب عليّ الليلة…‬
I guess you could say they weren't a tight-knit family.
‫يمكنك وصف عائلته بأنها مفككة.‬
I am…
‫أنا…‬
Tenma.
‫"تينما".‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Nice idea. I'd be glad to join you.
‫إنها لفكرة رائعة. يسرني أن أنضم إليكم.‬
KARAOKE PUB OEDO
‫"حانة كاريوكي (أويدو)"‬
Yay!
‫مرحى!‬
Way to go, Iwai!
‫أحسنت يا "إواي"!‬
How about a song, Inspector Lunge?
‫ما رأيك في أن تغني أغنية‬ ‫يا حضرة المفتش "لونغي"؟‬
Yeah!
‫أجل!‬
Oh, that's my song. Let's sing.
‫هذه أغنيتي. لنغنها.‬
-Let's hear it! -All right!
‫- لنسمعها!‬ ‫- حسنًا!‬
-Nice! Keep it up! -Way to go! Yahoo!
‫- أحسنتما! استمرا!‬ ‫- أحسنتما! مرحى!‬
I am Tenma.
‫أنا "تينما".‬
I do not fit into Japanese society.
‫أعجز عن الاندماج في المجتمع الياباني.‬
I won't ask for help now.
‫لن أطلب المساعدة الآن.‬
I have no place to call home.
‫أنا بلا ديار.‬
I am…
‫أنا…‬
alone.
‫وحيد.‬
Hey there. Domo, domo. Sorry I'm late.
‫مرحبًا. "دومو". أعتذر عن التأخر.‬
At last, you're here, Yamamoto.
‫أخيرًا وصلت يا "ياماموتو".‬
This is Inspector Lunge who I mentioned on the phone.
‫هذا هو المفتش "لونغي"‬ ‫الذي أخبرتك عنه على الهاتف.‬
Oh, domo. I'm Yamamoto of the Munich office of Kadofuku Corporation.
‫"دومو". أنا "ياماموتو" من فرع‬ ‫شركة "كادوفوكو" في "ميونخ".‬
Domo.
‫"دومو".‬
How did the meeting with Mr. Kocht in the Czech Republic go?
‫كيف كان اجتماعك مع السيد "كوخت"‬ ‫في جمهورية "التشيك"؟‬
He's a really tough customer.
‫إنه زبون صعب المراس.‬
Oh, that reminds me. I found that thing.
‫ذكّرني ذلك بما وجدته.‬
What thing?
‫ماذا وجدت؟‬
That thing Schuwald's secretary, that young blonde guy, wanted.
‫الشيء الذي أراده سكرتير "شوفالد" الأشقر.‬
What? Did you find that?
‫ماذا؟ وجدته؟‬
Right now, getting on his secretary's good side
‫حاليًا، نيل رضا سكرتيره‬
is the best way to get business done with Schuwald.
‫هو أمثل طريقة‬ ‫للدخول في مشروعات مع "شوفالد".‬
I went to a bunch of used book shops in Prague before I finally found a copy.
‫ذهبت إلى الكثير من متاجر الكتب المستعملة‬ ‫في "براغ" إلى أن وجدت نسخة أخيرًا.‬
So this is that picture book?
‫هذا هو الكتاب المصوّر إذًا؟‬
It's in pretty bad shape and the cover is gone,
‫حالته سيئة وليس له غلاف،‬
but if we wrap it up nicely, it will still impress him.
‫لكن إن اهتممنا بتغليفه، فسيبهره.‬
Excuse me. Beer, please.
‫من بعد إذنك، جعة من فضلك.‬
May I have a look?
‫هل لي أن ألقي نظرة؟‬
Sure, go right ahead.
‫بالتأكيد، تفضل.‬
It's in Czech.
‫إنه باللغة التشيكية.‬
Next is my song!
‫الأغنية التالية أغنيتي!‬
-Okay! Let's hear it! -All right!
‫- حسنًا! لنسمعها!‬ ‫- حسنًا!‬
Now for the real pro, huh?
‫حان وقت الغناء الاحترافي الآن.‬
All right!
‫أجل!‬
MUNICH POLICE
‫"شرطة (ميونخ)"‬
Inspector, what do you have that dictionary out for?
‫ما الغرض من هذا القاموس يا حضرة المفتش؟‬
-I'm translating Czech. -Czech?
‫- إنني أترجم التشيكية.‬ ‫- التشيكية؟‬
Is it related to the case?
‫ألهذا علاقة بالقضية؟‬
No, it has nothing to do with it.
‫لا، ليس له علاقة بها.‬
I never thought you'd investigate anything not related to a case.
‫ما كنت لأتصوّر أن تتحرّى عن أمر‬ ‫ليس له علاقة بقضية.‬
It's a picture book.
‫إنه كتاب مصوّر.‬
I like the drawings.
‫أحب الرسومات.‬
I wanted to know what the text meant.
‫أردت معرفة ما كُتب.‬
The inspector looking at a picture book? Never expected that.
‫يطالع المفتش كتابًا مصوّرًا؟‬ ‫ما كنت لأتوقع ذلك أبدًا.‬
"Look at me."
‫"انظر إليّ.‬
"The monster inside me has
‫الوحش بداخلي‬
grown so large," huh?
‫نما نموًا هائلًا"؟‬
I see. So Johan has finally started manipulating that bigwig.
‫فهمت. بدأ "يوهان" أخيرًا‬ ‫في التلاعب بتلك الشخصية البارزة.‬
Dr. Gillen, you told me before about this Johan guy.
‫سبق أن أخبرتني عن "يوهان" هذا‬ ‫يا د. "غيلن".‬
I can tell that Johan is a complete monster.
‫يمكن قول إن "يوهان" هذا‬ ‫بلغت وحشيته أقصى حد لها.‬
A monster, huh?
‫وحشيته؟‬
Yeah. I've killed a lot of people myself,
‫أجل، أنا عن نفسي قتلت الكثيرين،‬
but he's become the kind of person that I wanted to become.
‫لكنه أصبح ما أردت أن أكونه.‬
Johan's my hero now.
‫أصبح "يوهان" بطلي الآن.‬
I see. There's something else that I'd like to ask you.
‫فهمت. ثمة أمر آخر أود أن أسألك عنه.‬
Go ahead.
‫تفضل.‬
If you were Johan, what would you do next?
‫لو كنت أنت "يوهان"،‬ ‫فما الذي قد تفعله تاليًا؟‬
Do next?
‫ما أفعله تاليًا؟‬
Isn't it obvious?
‫أليس واضحًا؟‬
I'd murder his parents, the Lieberts.
‫كنت لأقتل والديه، آل "ليبرت".‬
Mr. Liebert!
‫سيد "ليبرت"!‬
Why would you do that?
‫لم قد تفعل ذلك؟‬
Don't you see? I got bored.
‫ألا تتبيّن السبب؟ لقد شعرت بالضجر.‬
Mr. Liebert!
‫سيد "ليبرت"!‬
Yes? Who are you?
‫نعم؟ من أنت؟‬
You're a psychologist?
‫أنت طبيب نفسي؟‬
I'm sorry, but what is it you want with us, Dr. Reichwein?
‫أعتذر عن ذلك ولكن ما الذي تريده منا‬ ‫يا د. "رايشفاين"؟‬
I won't waste your time with a long explanation.
‫لن أهدر لكما وقتكما بشرح مطوّل.‬
I've come to you about your adopted son, Johan.
‫جئت للتحدّث إليكما‬ ‫بشأن ابنكما المُتبنى "يوهان".‬
Johan? "Adopted?"
‫"يوهان"؟ "مُتبنى"؟‬
What are you talking about? That boy is our son.
‫عمّ تتحدث؟ إنه ابننا.‬
It's no use playing dumb.
‫التظاهر بالجهل لن ينفعكما.‬
The grave of your true son is in Bruntal.
‫قبر ابنكما الحقيقي في "برونتال".‬
You took advantage of the town records being destroyed in a fire
‫استغللتما تلف سجلات المدينة في الحريق‬
and applied for a new birth certificate to make it look like your child is alive.
‫وتقدّمتما بطلب لاستخراج شهادة ميلاد جديدة‬ ‫على أساس أن ابنكما لا يزال حيًا.‬
What are you implying?
‫إلام تلمّح؟‬
I didn't come here to threaten you.
‫لم آت لتهديدكما.‬
I came here for your own sakes.
‫جئت لمصلحتكما.‬
I'd like you to read this.
‫أريدكما أن تقرآ هذا.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
It's a report about Johan.
‫إنه تقرير عن "يوهان".‬
About Johan?
‫عن "يوهان"؟‬
Yes. It was compiled by a certain man.
‫أجل. كتبه شخص ما.‬
This man once visited to sell us insurance.
‫زارنا هذا الرجل ذات مرة ليبيعنا تأمينًا.‬
That's Richard Braun, a former police detective.
‫إنه "ريتشارد براون"، محقق سابق في الشرطة.‬
A former police detective?
‫محقق سابق في الشرطة؟‬
He's dead now.
‫لقد مات.‬
Now, read it.
‫اقرآه.‬
The story begins in 1986
‫بدأت القصة في عام 1986‬
when a certain East German government official defected to the west.
‫عندما انشق مسؤول ما عن "ألمانيا الشرقية"‬ ‫واتجه غربًا.‬
Is he after money?
‫أيريد المال؟‬
Money? No, he's not interested in money.
‫المال؟ لا، ليس مهتمًا بالمال.‬
Then why has he curried favor with a billionaire?
‫لم يتودد إلى مليونير إذًا؟‬
-Didn't you play that game as a kid? -What game?
‫- ألم تلعب تلك اللعبة في صغرك؟‬ ‫- أي لعبة؟‬
I'd find a line of ants…
‫أجد صفًا من النمل…‬
and I'd mess up their line and screw with them.
‫وأفسد للنمل صفه وأتلاعب به.‬
My god…
‫يا للهول…‬
I cannot possibly believe such a frightening story.
‫أعجز عن تصديق قصة مرعبة كهذه.‬
This is ludicrous.
‫هذا كلام فارغ.‬
I understand why you don't want to believe it.
‫أتفهم سبب عزوفكما عن تصديق هذا.‬
You lost your child when he was young.
‫فقدتما ابنكما في صغره.‬
You were never able to have more children.
‫وعجزتما عن إنجاب المزيد من الأطفال.‬
But then a young man showed up who was around
‫ثم ظهر شاب‬
the same age as your son, and he had money.
‫في مثل عمر ابنكما وكان معه مال.‬
He gave you this magnificent house.
‫منحكما هذا البيت المذهل.‬
He gave you this beautiful garden.
‫وتلك الحديقة الجميلة.‬
And he gave you love.
‫ومنحكما حبه.‬
I perfectly understand why you believe him.
‫أتفهم تمامًا سبب تصديقكما له.‬
However, the things in this report are the truth.
‫لكن ما ذُكر في هذا التقرير حقيقي.‬
Who is Johan?
‫من هو "يوهان"؟‬
Tell me who the heck he is!
‫أخبراني من يكون!‬
Johan is a good boy.
‫إن "يوهان" شاب صالح.‬
Johan is a kind boy.
‫وهو عطوف.‬
He's smart.
‫وذكي.‬
He's a clever boy.
‫إنه عبقري.‬
He's our reason for living.
‫من أجله نعيش.‬
Is that all?
‫أهذا كلّ ما تعرفانه؟‬
You've been playing his parents for five years,
‫بقيتكما تؤديان دور الوالدين له‬ ‫لخمسة أعوام،‬
but is that all you can say about him?
‫وهذا كل ما يسعكما إخباري به عنه؟‬
You know absolutely nothing about him!
‫أنتما لا تعرفان أي شيء عنه.‬
I'm begging you. I need your help.
‫أتوسل إليكما. أنا بحاجة إلى مساعدتكما.‬
Johan killed my friend Richard.
‫قتل "يوهان" صديقي "ريتشارد".‬
And right now, a man named Dr. Tenma is…
‫وحاليًا، ثمة رجل اسمه الدكتور "تينما"…‬
about to do the unthinkable.
‫على وشك الإقدام على تصرف لا يمكن تصوّره.‬
Please help me.
‫ساعداني من فضلكما.‬
More importantly,
‫الأهم من ذلك في حقيقة الأمر،‬
you will end up like the middle-aged couples in this report.
‫هو أن مصيركما سيكون كمصير‬ ‫من هم في منتصف العمر من الأزواج.‬
They were all foster parents who raised Johan. And they were…
‫كانوا جميعهم آباء بالتبني لـ"يوهان".  وهم…‬
all murdered.
‫قد قُتلوا جميعًا.‬
Please, leave this place with me.
‫اتركا هذا المكان معي من فضلكما.‬
The apple tree has sprouted some small fruit.
‫أنبتت شجرة التفاح حبات فاكهة صغيرة.‬
Yes. Next year, they'll be even bigger.
‫أجل. ستصبح أكبر من ذلك في العام المقبل.‬
I can hardly wait.
‫لا أطيق انتظار ذلك.‬
Yes. I can hardly wait too.
‫أجل. أنا أيضًا أتوق لذلك.‬
Johan told the children that he's about to be killed by a Japanese man?
‫أخبر "يوهان" الأطفال بأنه على وشك‬ ‫أن يموت على يد رجل ياباني؟‬
Yes. What do you think about what he said?
‫نعم. ما رأيك في كلامه هذا؟‬
To be frank, that guy doesn't have a death wish.
‫بصراحة، ليس لذلك الرجل رغبة في الموت.‬
Then what does it mean?
‫ما معنى ذلك إذًا؟‬
I'm not sure. It's hard to know what a hero is thinking.
‫لست متأكدًا.‬ ‫من الصعب معرفة ما قد يفكر فيه بطل.‬
But…
‫لكن…‬
But I can tell you this.
‫لكن ثمة ما أنا متأكد منه.‬
If the world ended in a nuclear war, he would survive it.
‫إن دُمّر العالم بحرب نووية، فسينجو.‬
I guess he means there's nothing we can do.
‫يعني بكلامه أنه لن يسعنا فعل أي شيء.‬
I will admit, everything we've done so far has been in vain.
‫أقرّ بأن كل ما فعلناه حتى الآن كان هباءً.‬
We couldn't even save Richard.
‫عجزنا حتى عن إنقاذ "ريتشارد".‬
Dr. Reichwein…
‫د. "رايشفاين"…‬
We haven't even been able to track down Dr. Tenma.
‫عجزنا حتى عن تقفي أثر الدكتور "تينما".‬
We can't even stop him trying to kill Johan. It's all been in vain!
‫لا يمكننا حتى ردعه عن محاولة قتل "يوهان".‬ ‫ذهب جهدنا بأكمله سدى.‬
Dr. Reichwein, we need to stay calm and think this over.
‫د. "رايشفاين"، يجب أن نحافظ على هدوئنا‬ ‫ونفكّر في تلك المسألة بتمعن.‬
I'm sorry.
‫أنا آسف.‬
Mess with a line of ants, huh?
‫يفسد للنمل صفه؟‬
Even ants have souls.
‫حتى النمل له روح.‬
Doctor, where are you going?
‫إلى أين تذهب يا دكتور؟‬
At this point, we must risk everything and bring the fight to him.
‫في هذه المرحلة يجب أن نخاطر بكل ما لدينا،‬ ‫ونجلب الصراع إليه.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
I'll meet with that mogul Schuwald and tell him everything we know.
‫سألتقي برجل الأعمال البارز "شوفالد"‬ ‫وأخبره بكل ما نعرفه.‬
What? Do they want 50 more chairs?
‫ماذا؟ تريد 50 كرسيًا غيرها؟‬
Dang, they are really packing them in.
‫اللعنة، إنهم يحشدون عددًا هائلًا.‬
Is this for Mr. Schuwald's book donation ceremony tomorrow?
‫أهذا من أجل حفل السيد "شوفالد"‬ ‫للتبرع بالكتب ليوم غد؟‬
Yeah. Important people are coming out of the woodwork to attend.
‫نعم. سيخرج أشخاص مهمين إلى العلن لحضوره.‬
Nowadays, anytime Mr. Schuwald makes a move, it's a huge deal.
‫في هذه الأيام أي خطوة‬ ‫يخطوها السيد "شوفالد" تحدث ضجة.‬
The library is about to close.
‫المكتبة على وشك أن تُغلق.‬
Excuse me.
‫المعذرة.‬
Sorry, but could you get that book for me?
‫أعتذر عن ذلك ولكن هلّا تحضر لي ذلك الكتاب.‬
It's that Czech dictionary. I can't reach it.
‫إنه قاموس تشيكي. أعجز عن الوصول إليه.‬
Oh, sure. This?
‫بالتأكيد. هذا؟‬
-Thank you, I appreciate it. -No problem.
‫- أشكرك. أنا ممتنة لك.‬ ‫- العفو.‬
I borrowed a Czech picture book, but I can't understand it.
‫استعرت كتابًا مصوّرًا تشيكيًا‬ ‫ولكنني أعجز عن فهمه.‬
Oh, I see…
‫مفهوم.‬
A friend of mine suddenly fainted when he read this picture book.
‫أُغمي فجأة على صديق لي‬ ‫عند قراءة هذا الكتاب المصوّر.‬
Really?
‫حقًا؟‬
I thought whatever is in this book might have had something to do with it.
‫خطر لي أن أيًا ما كان في هذا الكتاب‬ ‫قد يكون له علاقة بما حدث.‬
Is your friend all right now?
‫هل صديقك بخير الآن؟‬
Yes. He's just fine now.
‫نعم. إنه بخير الآن.‬
Thanks again.
‫أشكرك مجددًا.‬
No problem.
‫لا عليك.‬
Let's see here…
‫لنر…‬
"Once upon a time, in a land far away,
‫"كان يا مكان في مكان بعيد،‬
there lived a nameless monster."
‫عاش وحش بلا اسم.‬
"The monster was dying to have a name."
‫كان الوحش يرغب في أن يحظى باسم باستماتة.‬
"So he decided to set out on a journey."
‫لذلك قرر أن يخرج في رحلة."‬
What a strange book.
‫يا له من كتاب غريب.‬
We're closing.
‫سنغلق المكتبة.‬
Okay.
‫حسنًا.‬
We're closed tomorrow because of the ceremony.
‫ستكون المكتبة مغلقة غدًا بسبب الحفل.‬